Guide to the N. Scott Momaday Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers, 1788-2012; 1950s-2012
  - "Three Plays", 2006-07 (Box 79)
    MSS: "Three Plays": manuscript, page proofs, plus correspondence
  - "The Indolent Boys", 1994 (Box 79)
    One folder of P.R. materials/programs re: "The Indolent Boys" (play)
  - "Art Reviews", 1990-2006 (Box 79)
    One folder of reviews and articles re: N. Scott Momaday's artwork
  - "Oklahoma Centennial Poem", 2007 (Box 79)
    MSS: "Oklahoma 1907-2007": two drafts
  - "NM Comm Found. Event 7/20", 2007 (Box 79)
    One folder of business correspondence re: New Mexico Community Foundation event (July 2007)
  - "Blaisdell", 2007 (Box 79)
    One miscellaneous permission
  - "TX Wichita St. 11/16-7", undated (Box 79)
    One folder of miscellaneous mss. pages w/ corrections
  - "Lewis and Clark Essay--Josephy", 2003-05 (Box 79)
    MSS: "The Voices of Encounter": various drafts plus correspondence
  - "Misc. Permissions", 2007 (Box 79)
    One folder of miscellaneous permission requests
  - "Misc. Corres", 1991-2007 (Box 79)
    One folder of miscellaneous business correspondence
  - "Misc. MSS" (3), undated (Box 79)
    One folder of miscellaneous MSS: Incl. "Baseball"; "Oklahoma" poem, etc.
  - P.R. Materials/ Articles re: NSM", 1990-93 (Box 79)
    One folder of miscellaneous newspaper clippings, articles, publications, et. al. re: N. Scott Momaday
  - "Cookbook Intro", 2004 (Box 79)
    MSS: "Introduction" to Native Peoples Cookbook: draft w/ book plan 6pp
  - "White House Conference on Helping America's Youth", 2005 (Box 80)
    P.R. Materials re: The White House Conference on Helping America's Youth at Howard University, Washington DC: Participant's Notebook w/ schedules and invitation from President Bush (2005)
  - "Reflections of Hope Award", 2005 (Box 80)
    One large group of materials re: Oklahoma City National Memorial Foundation (April 19, 2005) (10th Year Anniversary) w/ copies of the Momaday broadside, "In the Spirit of Hope" and "The Official Record of the Oklahoma City Bombing"
  - "Disappointment Valley: A Modern Day Western", 2010 (Box 80)
    One folder of materials relating to the documentary, "Disappointment Valley, A Modern Day Western" concerning the American wild horse by James Anaquad Kleinert.
    DVD removed to Box 106.
  - "A Benign Self Portrait" (1), [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "A Benign Self Portrait: Poems": early typescript of this as-yet-unpublished poetry collection (unpaginated) ~250pp
  - "A Benign Self Portrait" (2), [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "A Benign Self Portrait: Poems": bound early typescript of this as-yet-unpublished poetry collection (unpaginated) ~250pp
  - "A Benign Self Portrait" (3), [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "A Benign Self Portrait: Poems": loose poems ~50pp
  - "The Places" (1) 1/5, [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "The Places" (Augusta, University of New Mexico, Dulce, Stanford, Santa Barbara): early typescript of this as-yet-unpublished memoir 111pp
  - "The Places" (1) 2/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (1) 3/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (1) 4/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (1) 5/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (2) 1/5, [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "The Places" (Augusta, University of New Mexico, Dulce, Stanford): partial early typescript of this as-yet-unpublished memoir 104pp
  - "The Places" (2) 2/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (2) 3/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (2) 4/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Places" (2) 5/5, [2012] (Box 81)
  - "The Saynday Monologues", [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "The Saynday Monologues": unpaginated, loose poetry collection ~75pp
  - "100 Haiku", [2012] (Box 81)
    MSS: "100 Haiku": poetry manuscript of one hundred numbered haiku poems 16pp
  - "The Momaday Gun", 2012 (Box 81)
    MSS: "The Momaday Gun": variant drafts of this piece re: Billy the Kid's gun, which Momaday purchased in 1983 4pp
  - "Essays", [2012] (Box 81)
    One folder of miscellaneous short pieces, fragments and essays. Includes material from "To Honor the Gift"; "Again the Far Morning"
  - "Poems", [2012] (Box 81)
    One large folder of miscellaneous poem drafts, mostly clean computer printouts
  - "The Indian in the Garden", undated (Box 81)
    MSS: "The Indian In the Garden" (a.k.a. "The Gardens of Time," "The Gardens of Time and Dreams): four variant drafts of this short piece w/ corrections 16pp
  - "To Build a Great Nation", undated (Box 81)
    MSS: "To Build a Great Nation": clean typescript of this poetry manuscript (unpg.) ~20pp
  - "Momaday--Boscacci Correspondence", 2012 (Box 81)
    One folder of personal correspondence (e-mail printouts) between N. Scott Momaday and Mary Jane Boscacci ~50pp
  - "Momaday--Spragg Correspondence", 2007-10 (Box 81)
    One folder of personal correspondence (e-mail printouts) between N. Scott Momaday and Stacia Spragg ~50pp
  - "Untitled Autobiographical Piece", 2011 (Box 81)
    MSS: Four-age holograph autobiographical piece by Momaday undated, plus a one-page reminiscence of Bubba Noel, of Kiowa heritage 4pp
  - "Misc. Poems", 2000-2011 (Box 81)
    MSS: One small folder of miscellaneous poem drafts, most clean, some signed and one two-page holograph poem, "The Pilgrim." Also includes miscellaneous correspondence.
  - HOLOGRAPH NOTEBOOK (1), 2008 (Box 81)
    NOTEBOOK: One original Cambridge notebook of holograph journal entries, Siberian train writings, letter drafts (J.M.G. LeClezio, Ken Burns, etc.), rough essay starts, et.al. (~30pp) ~30pp
  - HOLOGRAPH NOTEBOOK (2), undated (Box 81)
    NOTEBOOK: One original Rhodia notebook of miscellaneous holograph notes, poetry drafts, sketches, shopping lists, etc. 18pp
  - HOLOGRAPH NOTEBOOK (3), 2011-12 (Box 81)
    NOTEBOOK: "Diary 2012": One original Rhodia notebook of holograph journal entries starting from May 20, 2011 through June 4, 2012 (60pp) 60pp
  - HOLOGRAPH NOTEBOOK (4), undated (Box 81)
    NOTEBOOK: One original Rhodia notebook of holograph drafts of the "Dulce" section of "Places," plus drawings 27pp
  - HOLOGRAPH NOTEBOOK (5), 1998 (Box 81)
    NOTEBOOK: "Siberia Notes": One small, original Rhodia notebook of holograph drafts of the "Dulce" section of "Places," plus drawings 40pp
  - HOLOGRAPH NOTEBOOK (6), 2004 (Box 81)
    NOTEBOOK: One original partial Russian notebook of miscellaneous holograph notes (4pp) 4pp
  - LOOSE NOTES, undated (Box 81)
    LOOSE NOTES: Two small groups of loose miscellaneous notes 19pp
  - "Portrait of a Generation", (2010) (Box 81)
    MSS: "Portrait of a Generation: The Children of Oklahoma" by M.J. Alexander: sample pages and photographs from this book w/ holograph cover letter undated
  - "Making Do", 2011 (Box 81)
    MSS: "Making Do: Survival Ceremonies in a Hostile World" by Kenneth M. Roemer: typescript of a paper delivered at the 1-9-2011 MLA Conference in Los Angeles
  - "Again the Far Morning (ORIGINAL ART), 2011 (Box 82)
    ORIGINAL ARTWORK: "Again the Far Morning": Eleven original signed watercolor-and-ink illustrations (12" x 10") signed by N. Scott Momaday
  - "Scott Momaday: The Man made of Visions" (PORTFOLIO), 2011 (Box 82)
    PORTFOLIO: "Scott Momaday: The Man made of Visions" (Paris, FRANCE: ORENDA Art International, 2011): Number 25 of a total of 100 copies. An edition of eleven printed poems and twelve numbered-and-signed full-color prints in embossed leather folder w/ monogrammed pen laid in. An elaborate and beautiful production
  - "The Moon in Two Windows", (2007) (Box 83)
    MSS: "The Moon in Two Windows: A Screenplay": spiral-bound clean typescript undated 97pp
  - "The Indolent Boys", (2007) (Box 83)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": clean typescript of this play (unpg.) ~100pp
  - "Beyond the Silence of Sorrow", 2002 (Box 83)
    SHEET MUSIC: "Beyond the Silence of Sorrow: for Soprano & Piano" by Roberto Sierra. Words by N. Scott Momaday (Subito Music Publishing, 2002) w/ holograph cover letter from Roberto Sierra
    Two CD's of the piece removed to Box 107.
  - "Children of the Sun", 2000 (Box 83)
    NOTEBOOK: "Children of the Sun" (play): original holograph notebook of poems and appreciation presented to N. Scott Momaday by the cast members of the Barter Theatre (Abingdon, VA)
  - "INSURANCE" 1/2, 1997-2004 (Box 83)
    FINANCIAL: One large group of folder re: Momaday's car and home owner's insurance
  - "INSURANCE" 2/2, 1997-2004 (Box 83)
  - "CONTRACTS" 1/3, 2005 (Box 83)
    CONTRACTS: Two folders of business correspondence and contracts from the University of Arizona and The Institute of American Indian Affairs (2005)
  - "CONTRACTS" 2/3, 2005 (Box 83)
  - "CONTRACTS" 3/3, 2005 (Box 83)
  - "MEDICAL", 1998-2002 (Box 83)
    MEDICAL RECORDS: One group of photocopies of N. Scott's medical records from 1998-2002
  - "Literature and Culture", 1989 (Box 83)
    B.A. THESIS: "Literature and Culture: The Emergence and Implications of Native American Literature in the 1960s and 1970s" by Katherine S. Gunness (Princeton NJ, 1989): bound thesis 103+pp
  - "Woman of Tonalea", 1986 (Box 83)
    GREETING CARDS: "Woman of Tonalea": multiple copies an N. Scott Momaday-designed watercolor greeting card
  - "Irina", 1986 (Box 83)
    GREETING CARDS: "Irina": multiple copies an N. Scott Momaday-designed gouache greeting card
  - "World Literature Today", 2007 (Box 83)
    OFFPRINT: "When Dogs Could Talk: Among Words in a State of Grace" by N. Scott Momaday: multiple copies
  - MISCELLANEOUS, var. (Box 83)
    MISCELLANEOUS: One large folder of miscellaneous correspondence, flyers, maps, stationary, et. al.
  - ADDRESS BOOKS, 1982-90 (Box 83)
    Two telephone/address books c. 1982, plus one day planner from 1989-90
  - School of American Research 1/2, 2000s (Box 83)
  - School of American Research 2/2, 2000s (Box 83)
  - BOOKMARK, 1989 (Box 83)
    BOOKMARK: One personalized cloth-and-metal bookmark from The Tattered Cover bookstore in Denver, CO, presented to N. Scott Momaday Oct. 13, 1989
  - "Children of the Sun", undated (Box 84)
    MSS: "Children of the Sun": three photocopies of the author's copy 33pp
  - "Lewis and Clark Through Indian Eyes", 2005 (Box 84)
    MSS: "Lewis and Clark Through Indian Eyes" (w/ N. Scott Momaday's contribution "the Voices of Encounter"): page proofs sent to Momaday for correction, plus publisher's cover letter (Knopf), plus corres. re: untimely death of editor Alvin M. Josephy; and additional "Prologue" 204pp
  - "Buffalo Trust", 2003-04 (Box 84)
    One large group of business and organizational materials re: The Buffalo Trust, Santa Fe NM, 2003-04
  - "Sovereignty", undated (Box 84)
    MS: "Sovereignty": two clean drafts of this essay 15pp
  - "Language, the Fifth Element", 2005 (Box 84)
    MS: "Language, the Fifth Element": typescript of this lecture given at St. John's Lecture on January 18, 2005, "for personal use only," and correspondence 23pp
    Audio CD of the lecture, recorded on March 10, 2005, removed to Box 106.
  - "Prayers, Poems, Songs, Misc.", undated (Box 84)
    MSS: One folder of miscellaneous poetry drafts
  - "May It Be Beautiful", undated (Box 84)
    MS: "May It Be Beautiful": clean drafts of this short piece 2pp
  - "The Literary Commons", undated (Box 84)
    MS: "The Literary Commons": four-page essay re: UNESCO w/ holograph emendations 4pp
  - "A Man Who Made Rainbows", 1999 (Box 84)
    MS: "A Man Who Made Rainbows": three-page typescript re: Momaday's father, dated November 2, 1999 3pp
  - "A First American Views His Land", undated (Box 84)
    MS: ""A First American Views His Land": clean typescript of this essay 7pp
  - "Heritage, Healing and the Land: The Spiritual Aspect of Landscape", undated (Box 84)
    MS: "Heritage, Healing and the Land: The Spiritual Aspect of Landscape": two variant drafts of this essay 15pp
  - "Indian Writers: Is America Ready for Your Message?", 1977 (Box 84)
    MS: "Indian Writers: Is America Ready for Your Message?" by Dee Brown: typescript of a speech that references Momaday (Symposium of the American Indian, April 1977) 14pp
  - REVIEWS//TEARSHEETS, 1992-2006 (Box 84)
    One large group of reviews, tearsheets, publications and p.r. materials re: N. Scott Momaday
  - "Brainstorm 2001" (Box 84)
    CONFERENCE CATALOGUE: "Brainstorm 2001: The FORTUNE editors' invitational": ringbound conference guide in which N. Scott Momaday was an invited participant
  - "The Indolent Boys" (1), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": bound typescript w/ Momaday's pencil notes and corrections (w/ Momaday's Tucson address) 70pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (2), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": variant typescript (clean) (w/ Momaday's Tucson address) 76pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (3), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": typescript w/ heavy corrections in blue pen throughout (w/ Momaday's Tucson address) 76pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (4), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": typescript w/ heavy corrections in blue pen throughout and editorial comments on title page (w/ Momaday's Tucson address) 72pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (5), 1994 (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": clean variant typescript dated 11/7/94 (w/ Momaday's Tucson studio address) 79pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (6), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": clean variant typescript (no address) 79pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (7), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": photocopied variant typescript (mixed fonts) w/ corrections (with both Tucson addresses) 79pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (8), [1994] (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": clean variant typescript and partial ts. (Tucson address) 79pp
  - "The Indolent Boys" (9), undated (Box 85)
    MSS: "The Indolent Boys": two copies of a later, unpaginated (finished?) version (w/ Jemez Springs, NM address) 84pp
  - "Der Weg Nach Rainy Mountain", 1991 (Box 85)
    MS: "Der Weg Nach Rainy Mountain": photocopy of the German language typescript, translated by Matthias Schubnell (119pp + 3pp addendum) 122pp
  - "Beyond the Silence of Sorrow", [2002] (Box 85)
    MS: "Beyond the Silence of Sorrow": unpaginated poetry typescript w/ numerous fonts and Sante Fe address ~100pp
  - "Vine Tribute", 2005 (Box 85)
    MS: "An Honor Song in the Old Style: For Vine Deloria Jr.": drafts of a poem in Honor of Native American author and activist Vine Deloria Jr. (2005), plus correspondence 1p
  - "Fritz Scholder", 2005 (Box 85)
    MS: "Fritz Scholder": multiples drafts of a tribute essay to painter Fritz William Scholder (1937-2005), plus attendant memorial materials and correspondence 6pp
  - "Children of the Sun" (1), 2002 (Box 85)
    MS: "Children of the Sun": two clean typescripts 33pp
  - "Children of the Sun" (2), 2002 (Box 85)
    MS: "Children of the Sun": typescript w/ corrections, plus signed contract for French edition 33pp
  - "Children of the Sun" (3), 2002 (Box 85)
    MS: "Children of the Sun": artwork and correspondence with Federica Matta (artist) and Daniele Laruelle (French translator)
  - "Children of the Sun" (4), 2002 (Box 85)
    MSS: "Children of the Sun: A Story and a Play": two typescripts of the revised (children's) version 15pp
  - "St. Martin's Contracts", 2002 (Box 85)
    One large folder of contracts between NSM and St. Martin's Press 15pp
  - REVIEWS//TEARSHEETS, 1962-2004 (Box 85)
    One large group of reviews, clippings, tearsheets, publications and p.r. materials re: N. Scott Momaday (includes his essay "The Native Voice in American Literature", 22pp)
  - "Ken Roemer" (Rainy Mountain), 1990 (Box 85)
    PHOTOGRAPHS: Three full-color photographs of Rainy Mountain in folder w/ holograph letter to NSM from photographer Ken Roemer dated 3/28/90
  - "Nobel Correspondence", 2004-05 (Box 85)
    One folder of business correspondence re: Nobel Prize for Literature
  - "Universite Blaise Pascal", 2003 (Box 85)
    One folder of business correspondence re: Honorary Doctorate of Universite Blaise Pascal (Warsaw, POLAND, 2003)
  - "The Moon in Two Windows" (1), 2001 (Box 86)
    MSS: "The Moon in Two Windows": Bound, revised typescript dated March 7, 2001 93pp
  - "The Moon in Two Windows" (2), 2001 (Box 86)
    MSS: "The Moon in Two Windows": Revised typescript dated April 4, 2002 95pp
  - "The Moon in Two Windows" (3), 2005 (Box 86)
    MSS: "The Moon in Two Windows": Clean typescript (two copies) 97pp
  - "The Moon in Two Windows" (4), 2005 (Box 86)
    MSS: "The Moon in Two Windows": Spiral-bound typescript 97pp
  - "The Land", 2005 (Box 86)
    MSS: "The Land": two variant typescripts of this prose piece with editorial note by Momaday at the top of Copy #2 101pp
  - BIO-BIBLIOGRAPHY, 2008 (Box 86)
    MS: "N. Scott Momaday: Remembering Ancestors, Earth & Traditions: Poet, Author, Artist, Educator" by Phyllis S. Morgan (2008): extensive bio-bibliography (published?) 216+pp
  - "Language, The Fifth Element", 2005 (Box 86)
    MSS: "Language, The Fifth Element": three clean typescripts of this lecture, dated January 18, 2005 33pp
  - "Kiowa Road", 1977-83 (Box 86)
    MS: "Kiowa Road" by Kiowa Tribe of Oklahoma (Carnegie, OK: December 1983): a manuscript of summaries of taped conversations w/ Kiowa elders re: the history of the tribe (unpaginated) ~30pp
  - "Siberia Trip", 2008 (Box 86)
    One folder of travel and business materials re: Momaday's Trans-Siberia Rail College Trip (2008)
  - "Travel Expenses and Amex", 2006-07 (Box 86)
    One folder of travel and business materials, receipts, etc. (2006-2007)
  - REVIEWS//TEARSHEETS, 1991-2008 (Box 86)
    One small group of miscellaneous reviews, tearsheets, publications and p.r. materials re: N. Scott Momaday
  - "Joe D. Kirkwood", 2004 (Box 86)
    ARTIST BOOKS: "The Sacred Circle of the Dakotas" and "Following the Path of the Sun" by Joe D. Kirkwood (Flaming Rose Books, 2004): two string-bound artist books of poetry inscribed by author
  - "Cathy Notarnicola", undated (Box 86)
    ACADEMIC PAPER: "The Illustration of Oral Traditions in Navajo Weavings" by Cathy Notarnicola: bound academic paper with glowing note from NSM (A+)
  - "First Nations Development Institute" (1), 2002 (Box 86)
    BUSINESS MATERIALS: "First Nations Development Institute: Board of Directors Conference Call: June 7, 2002; 10:00 a.m.-12:00 noon EST" ~200pp
  - "First Nations Development Institute" (2), 2001-02 (Box 86)
    BUSINESS MATERIALS: One folder of financial reports and business correspondence re: First Nations Development Institute
  - "First Nations Development Institute" (3), 1999-2001 (Box 86)
    BUSINESS MATERIALS: One huge folder of financial reports and business correspondence re: First Nations Development Institute
  - "International Achievement Summit" (1), 2002 (Box 90)
    One ringbound notebook of business materials re: International Achievement Summit, June 6-9, 2002, Dublin, IRELAND
  - "International Achievement Summit" (2), 2004 (Box 90)
    One ringbound notebook of business materials re: International Achievement Summit, June 10-14, 2004, Chicago, IL
  - "International Achievement Summit" (3), 2005 (Box 90)
    One ringbound notebook of business materials re: International Achievement Summit, June 1-4, 2005, New York NY
  - "International Achievement Summit" (4), 2001 (Box 90)
    One ringbound notebook of business materials re: International Achievement Summit, May 3-6 2001, San Antonio TX
  - "American Indian Warriors Today", 1998 (Box 90)
    Ph.D. THESIS: "American Indian Warriors Today" by J. Boyd Morningstorm (University of Arizona, 1998) (in blue ring binder) 211pp
  - "School of American Research", 2002-03 (Box 90)
    One disbound notebook of business materials re: the School of American Research Collections Committee (Indian Arts Research Center, August 14, 2003)
  - "Merna R. Lomack", undated (Box 91)
    One unpaginated poetry ms. by Merna R. Lomack, Fairbanks AK undated
  - "Diane Benson" (1), undated (Box 91)
    One unpaginated poetry ms. by Diane Benson, plus reviews and offprints
  - "Diane Benson" (2), 2001 (Box 91)
    MS: "Our Indians, Our Sofa": playscript, plus additional clippings and academic materials 10pp
  - "Buffalo Trust" (1), 2007-08 (Box 91)
    One folder of income tax materials re: The Buffalo Trust
  - "Buffalo Trust" (2), 2004-09 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and grant materials re: The Ford Foundation grant to the Buffalo Trust
  - "Oklahoma Film Project", 2005 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and notes re: Buffalo Trust film project
  - "Plays Project" ("Three Plays"), 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence, notes and contracts re: "Three Plays" book
  - "UNM Press", 2002-04 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and royalty statements re: University of New Mexico Press
  - "Rick Ardinger/Limberlost Press", 2005 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence w/ Rick Ardinger, Limberlost Press chapbook project
  - "People's Archive", 2005 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence re: People's Archive
  - "Jack Gibbons", 2005 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence w/ Jack Gibbons re: Poem Lyric Project
  - "Royce Carlton Inc.", 2004 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence w/ Royce Carlton Inc. re: catalogue and bio
  - "St. Martin's Press Rights Reversion", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business and legal correspondence re: St. Martin's Press
  - "Oklahoma Art 9/4/06", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and promo materials re: JRB Art at the Elms
  - "Nunavut 9/7-15", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and travel materials re: Alaska trip
  - "IAIA Class Spr. '06", 2006 (Box 91)
    ACADEMIC: One folder of academic materials, syllabus, student correspondence and papers re: IAIA Museum class (Spring 2006)
  - "IAIA Grant", 2004-05 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence, grant application and mission statements re: USDA Grant, Buffalo Trust and IAIA
  - "IAIA Contract and Events", 2005 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and contracts re: IA IA Lecture
  - "St. Louis L&C 9/20", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence re: National Council of Lewis & Clark
  - "S.A.R. Current", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and materials re: School of American Research
  - "New Empl. S.A.R.", 2004-05 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and contracts re: School of American Research
  - "Misc. Projects and Invites 2005" (Box 91)
    One folder of miscellaneous business correspondence from 2005
  - "Helsinki 5/14-20", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of miscellaneous business correspondence re: Finland trip
  - "Helsinki 5/16-19/06", 2005-06 (Box 91)
    One folder of miscellaneous business correspondence and travel materials re: Finland trip
  - "Autry Current", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence re: Autry National Center
  - "Phyllis Morgan", 2004-05 (Box 91)
    One large folder of business correspondence and early drafts of N. Scott Momaday's Bio-Bibliography
  - "Rainy Mountain Church and Comm.", 2003-05 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and materials re: Rainy Mountain Kiowa Indian Baptist Church (Mountain View, OK)
  - "Ted Turner", 2002 (Box 91)
    One draft of a two-page letter from NSM to Ted Turner
  - "BT--Okla//Corresp & Contacts", 2003-04 (Box 91)
    One large folder of business correspondence, project proposals and business cards re: Buffalo Trust
  - "Indian Market 2005" (Box 91)
    One small folder of misc. Indian arts w/ two photos of NSM
  - "Robert Henry", 2004-05 (Box 91)
    One folder of correspondence w/ Judge Robert Henry, plus copies of CROSSTIMBERS magazine
  - "Robert Henry", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and materials re: St. John's College
  - "Momaday", 2006 (Box 91)
    One folder of business correspondence and materials re: Momaday and St. John's College
  - "Futures 9/29-30, Santa Fe", 2006 (Box 91)